<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dave Svatora</title>
    <link>https://davesvatora.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dave Svatora</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 08:42:06 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davesvatora.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Samba</title>
      <link>https://davesvatora.github.io/computers_and_stuff/samba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 08:42:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davesvatora.github.io/computers_and_stuff/samba/</guid>
      <description>I want to create shared folder that I can access from any device on my local network so I decided to try out Samba to get some experience. I&#39;m mainly using this guide, but my notes will be a scaled down version. Ubuntu also has a great tutorial here
Installation sudo apt install samba Verify Installation with: whereis samba
Users and Groups We want to create a samba user and group and add our user to the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi4</title>
      <link>https://davesvatora.github.io/computers_and_stuff/pi4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 21:49:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davesvatora.github.io/computers_and_stuff/pi4/</guid>
      <description>I got a Raspberry Pi 4 recently to play around with on some home projects. I am going to try to see if its functional as a developer machine as well as run some dockerized apps on it. This post will document my experience and steps to get stuff up and running. Most of the documentation I do is essentially bread crumbs that I can later use to recreate something if I decide to blow it away and start over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutrition</title>
      <link>https://davesvatora.github.io/about_me/nutrition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 17:52:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davesvatora.github.io/about_me/nutrition/</guid>
      <description>Over the last 3-4 years I&#39;ve become more and more interested in nutrition and diet. My wakeup call was having blood analysis tests done and not having the best results. Up to that point in my life I never really cared that much about calories, salt, sugar or much of any type of food intake considerations. I would say my diet at the time was typical American and consisted of meats, cheese, chips, bread, and way too much sugar and salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini ITX</title>
      <link>https://davesvatora.github.io/computers_and_stuff/mini_itx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 13:09:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davesvatora.github.io/computers_and_stuff/mini_itx/</guid>
      <description>It started off with just upgrading the i3 processor&amp;hellip;  &amp;hellip;and turned into a bad a$$ custom built machine you can&#39;t get anywhere. My first debate was to buy a 3 year old i7 for ~$300 or get a fairly new Ryzen 5 with 6 cores and 12 threads for half the cost. I&#39;ve been an AMD fan for years but didn&#39;t have good experiences with bulldozer or the Ryzen 5 2400G (Didn&#39;t play well with Linux).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinuxSoftware</title>
      <link>https://davesvatora.github.io/computers_and_stuff/linux_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 13:08:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davesvatora.github.io/computers_and_stuff/linux_software/</guid>
      <description>Pop!_OS has a built in software distribution gui called the Pop!_Shop. In this guide we&#39;ll start off by installing some common software one might use on a linux machine for general use. Like most built in software management gui&#39;s on Linux there is some software available, but its hit or miss. After the easy installs we&#39;ll add in more using apt.
Lets start off with easy installs from the Pop!_Shop</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://davesvatora.github.io/syntax/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 13:08:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davesvatora.github.io/syntax/markdown/</guid>
      <description>Headings Headings from h1 through h6 are constructed with a # for each level:
# h1 Heading ## h2 Heading ### h3 Heading #### h4 Heading ##### h5 Heading ###### h6 Heading Renders to:
h1 Heading h2 Heading h3 Heading h4 Heading h5 Heading h6 Heading HTML:
&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;h1 Heading&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;h2 Heading&amp;lt;/h2&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;h3 Heading&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;h4 Heading&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h5&amp;gt;h5 Heading&amp;lt;/h5&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h6&amp;gt;h6 Heading&amp;lt;/h6&amp;gt; Comments Comments should be HTML compatible
&amp;lt;!--This is a comment --&amp;gt; Comment below should NOT be seen:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortcodes Examples</title>
      <link>https://davesvatora.github.io/syntax/shortcodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davesvatora.github.io/syntax/shortcodes/</guid>
      <description>The notice shortcode shows 4 types of disclaimers to help you structure your page.
Note {{% notice note %}} A notice disclaimer {{% /notice %}} renders as
A notice disclaimer
 Info {{% notice info %}} An information disclaimer {{% /notice %}} renders as
An information disclaimer
 Tip {{% notice tip %}} A tip disclaimer {{% /notice %}} renders as
A tip disclaimer
 Warning {{% notice warning %}} An warning disclaimer {{% /notice %}} renders as</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>